an alternative approach to trying to
create better
solutions for sequential consistency
which programmers naturally might expect
is to actually relax the consistency
that is we tell the programmers that
they cannot really expect sequential
consistency but we can still tell them
that they can expect something
and these relaxed consistency models
that are not really sequential
consistency but they're not just like
anything goes
usually differ in terms of what types of
ordering do they enforce there are
really four types of ordering
there is ordering between rights to
different locations
there are orderings between rights to
some locations and raids of other
locations there is ordering between
reads and subsequent writes in program
order between reads and other reads in
program order sequential consistency
says that basically program execution
must obey all four types of ordering at
all times if we actually reorder
something we have to fix any situation
where that would result in a different
outcome
than
program order execution so we are
allowed to reorder things but we have to
always hide that from anybody being able
to see it in relaxed consistency models
some of these types of ordering need not
be obeyed at all times usually the first
type of ordering that will not be obeyed
is the read read so if we maintain
the ordering between writes and between
writes and reads but just allow reads to
proceed out of order then we say that we
have a less relaxed model than if we
allow reordering of other types so if we
told the programmers
that you have to write programs
without assuming
that reads are done
in correct order then the real question
is but how do we then write correct
programs to begin with so for example
how do we do flag synchronization
if we cannot expect that
after waiting on a flag
we will be able to read the new value of
the data